Hi everyone, welcome to the quick tutorial series of Marlboro's Designer 2025 version.
In this tutorial, we will introduce how to create a version in Marlboro's Designer.
First, we can load a virtual model to create a costume.
Click on the icon in the upper right corner and open the window.
Go to the virtual model label and open the female model folder.
Click and drag the virtual model to the 3D window, or double click on its icon to load the virtual model.
In Marlboro's Designer, if you need to create a simple and tight costume structure, you can remove the template from the virtual model.
In the 3D tool bar, find the virtual model in the 3D pen.
Click on the model icon in the 3D pen.
Follow the instructions of the virtual model.
When the virtual model is on the virtual model, there is a black dot that moves with the virtual model to show us the straight line.
From the start, click on the left mouse button to create a straight line.
Then move the mouse down.
You can see that there is a line that appears along with the movement of the mouse.
At this time, press the Shift key to continue moving the mouse.
You can see that no matter how you move the mouse, the black dot and the straight line will only be created along the reference line.
Then follow the steps in the video.
Click on a dot at the top right corner.
Then click on a dot at the side line of the waist.
At this time, release the Shift key and create a night well point along the side.
Press the Ctrl key and click on the virtual model.
You can create a curve point at the click position to control the curve of the line.
When you press the Ctrl key, the created point will change from a straight line point to a curve point.
Release the Ctrl key and you can continue to create a straight line point.
Each curve needs a straight line point to interrupt.
After completing a pure straight line line, continue to draw the neck curve.
Finally, click on the neck curve to complete a closed shape.
When the shape is closed, you will see that all the lines that make up this shape will turn yellow.
Try this area and you can take it as a board.
Next, let's start from the outer point of the back piece.
Pay attention when drawing the dragon line.
Because we are drawing a curve line on the surface of the 3D model,
sometimes a simple curve line may cross some uneven areas.
When we create a line, try to draw it in an even position.
Complete the creation of other lines.
Start from the bottom point of the side waist and press the Shift key.
Create a straight line at the back of the level and a straight line at the back of the number.
Continue to create the neck curve and complete the closed shape.
I remind you again to press the Ctrl key to create a curve point.
Check if there are any unfinished lines and unclosed shapes.
When the side panels are created, use the scale as a panel tool.
Select the front panel and the selected area will be displayed as yellow.
Press the Enter key to extract it as a panel.
After extracting, panels appear at the same time in the 3D and 2D windows.
At this time, you can see that the front of the panel has been extracted into a curve.
Although we draw lines along the vertical direction when we draw the model,
because it is created on the surface of the model, it may be a curve.
Press the Ctrl key to return to the previous step of the extract panel.
Use the 3D pen to select the front middle line.
Press the Right key to select the vertical line.
Then you can see that this line has been increased.
After these stitches are added to the model, they will be leveled into straight lines.
And then we will delineate the other lines, such as the passage penetrating line, the back middle line and the indirect line,
and we will delineate them as straight lines.
Returning to the level it as panel with sliced ρ,
press Shift key to select more to select both areas.
Then press the ENTER key, and the two shapes will be flattened into a board.
After that, you can see that the front, back, side and shoulder lines are all straight lines.
At this time, if you switch to any tool in the sewing line tool group, you will see that the shoulder line and side line positions automatically create the sewing line.
This is because when flattening the board, the line positions shared between the boards will automatically generate the sewing line.
Then switch to the adjustment board tool and select these two boards.
On the selected board, right-click, select the symmetrical board, board and sewing line functions, and create a new board on the other side.
After creating the board, you can press the SHIFT key to open the guide line and place the board in the horizontal direction.
Next, we are going to sew the front and back sides separately.
Switch to the line sewing tool.
This tool can quickly create the sewing line between the lines and the lines.
Click on one side of the line, then click on the other side of the line, and then you will create a good sewing line.
When using it, pay attention that the sewing line has a direction. We want to ensure that the direction is the same.
Then press the SHIFT key to open the guide line, and you can see that the vest is done.
After that, we will learn more about the system.
We can draw the board in the 2D window.
If you don't have the board knowledge, it doesn't matter. We can download some sample pictures on the website as reference pictures.
Right-click on the background of the 2D window and select the setting 2D background option.
Click on the file folder icon to find a suitable reference picture.
Click on open and download the sample picture.
Click and drag the background picture to adjust its position.
You can align the front middle line to the front middle line of the virtual model, and the shoulder incision point to the shoulder incision point of the virtual model.
Then we refer to the bottom of the virtual model.
Along the shape, extend to the shoulder, and compare the shoulder of the reference picture.
You can also refer to the widest part of the front. Usually, the widest part of the front waist should be 2 to 1.5 times the most detailed part of the human body incision waist.
After comparison, we will find that the proportion of this reference picture needs to be smaller.
Set the size to 90%, and compare the shoulder position again to confirm the size.
Then we can start to draw the version according to the reference picture.
First of all, we can use a multidirectional tool.
Start from the neck point and draw the version.
It is similar to the version drawn in the 3D window.
Create a line section by creating a point.
During the drawing process, a pink intelligent guide line will appear.
It is used to mark the position of the line in the same level and vertical direction as other points.
You can also use the Shift key to create vertical and horizontal lines along the reference line direction.
Press Ctrl key and click to create a curve line.
Then release the Ctrl key and continue to click to create a curve line.
Repeat the operation of the line point.
Finally, click to close the point and complete the closed shape.
After the closed shape is completed, the corresponding line will be created.
Then start to draw the sleeve line.
Start to draw from the sleeve mountain.
Press Ctrl key and click to draw the line point.
During the drawing process, you can press the Shift key to return to the previous point.
Press the Esc key or Ctrl key to cancel the whole shape creation.
Then complete the sleeve creation.
From the sleeve mountain to the seam line, then the sleeve mouth.
When creating the sleeve mouth, move the mouse to see the pink intelligent guide line.
Because we will later open this left and right symmetrical sleeve version,
we need to create a vertical line for the top of the sleeve mountain.
Half of the sleeve is completed.
We can switch back to the edit sheet tool, select the middle line,
press the right key and select open in the pop-up menu.
After the selection opens, the sheet will open along the selected line.
But when we adjust to one side of the sheet, the other side will not be changed at the same time.
We will return to the previous step.
Also, when doing the editing operation, for example, when dragging the line point,
press the Esc key or Ctrl key to cancel the operation.
Then, the back.
For the back, we change the way of creating a fill.
Try other tools.
Select the rectangle tool,
to create a rectangular panel by referring to the width and focus points of the back piece.
We can modify the display type of the panel to a semi-transparent surface or a full-transparent surface
to refer to the negative points that are blocked.
Next, select the plus point division tool,
click on the focus point and the bottom point to create a straight line point.
Then, adjust the position of the other straight lines with the edge panel tool.
Use the edge panel tool to click and drag a straight line to form a panel.
During the dragging process, you can adjust the frequency of this panel.
Of course, you can also create a new panel
after creating it.
Next, use the edge panel tool to drag and adjust it.
Change back to the edge panel tool.
You can see that the edge panel line created by the edge panel tool is controlled by the control lever of the Beiser curve line.
Drag the control lever to adjust the curve line.
In addition, when using the edge panel tool,
press the Alt key to make the Beiser curve line related command.
For example, if you press the Alt key and drag a line,
you can change it to the Beiser curve line.
Press the Alt key to drag a point,
you can add two opposite control lines on the point.
Press the Alt key to drag a control line,
you can separate a control line on the point.
Select the control line and press the Delete key,
you can change the curve of this side to a straight line.
Press the Alt key to drag a control line on the point,
The curve of the previous model
needs to be adjusted by the edge panel tool.
Only by selecting the edge panel tool
can you see these curve points.
Click and drag these curve points to adjust the curve line.
After completing this panel,
you can select the center line,
then select the edge panel tool to edit the curve to give the line a shape.
At this time, the back panel will
turn into an elliptical figure with a left and a right symmetry,
the middle panel will be the point.
If I adjust the line on one side,
I will also do the same on the other side.
But the panel is still a complete panel,
For the front and sleeves, we can create a symmetrical version.
Press Shift and select the front and sleeves.
In the menu in the right-hand corner, select the symmetrical version, version and sewing line.
The version created in this way will be synchronized with the original version and the sewing line.
According to the smart guide line, click the right position to place the version of the cologne.
Next, let's draw the pocket version.
First, draw an internal rectangle.
On the version, click and hold the left mouse button and drag the mouse to draw a rectangle.
Use the plus point line tool to create a two-point point on the bottom of the line according to the pink smart guide.
Go back to the previous step.
Use the edit version tool.
First, click on the blank to cancel a whole line.
Then select the bottom line of the pocket separately.
Through the right-click menu of the plus point line tool, you can select the line after selecting the middle line and then select the middle line.
Then use the deep circle to draw a line tool.
Click and drag the straight line to create the corner of the pocket.
To see clearly.
Then select the inner line on the panel.
Change the
Then we need to take the pocket from the inner line as a panel.
Then we will divide this panel into the inner line.
Choose the cologne outline tool.
Then select the inner line section of the pocket.
Start by drawing a line in the middle.
Then draw a line from the middle and a line from the bottom of the pocket one by one.
It will look like this.
This is the process of creating panels.
See you next time.